<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bryan W Kettle</title><link>https://bryanisonline.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Bryan W Kettle</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 15:37:48 -0330</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bryanisonline.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Research</title><link>https://bryanisonline.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 15:35:50 -0330</pubDate><guid>https://bryanisonline.github.io/research/</guid><description>Overview A general theme in mathematics is to understand out how use established techniques and theory to help solve more complicated questions. Representation theory is the study of understanding abstract algebraic objects through the lens of linear algebra by representing abstract elements as matrices. In effect, representation theory allows one to use the power and tools of linear algebra to understand far more complicated objects.
One definition of quantum algebra is that it is the area of mathematics that in some way relates to the fact that noncommutivity (that is, when $a \star b \neq b \star a$) is found in quantum mechanics.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://bryanisonline.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 15:34:37 -0330</pubDate><guid>https://bryanisonline.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Email: bkettle(at)ualberta.ca
Or message me on LinkedIn
Address CAB 548
Department of Mathematical and Statistical Sciences
University of Alberta
116 St &amp;amp; 85 Ave
Edmonton, AB</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://bryanisonline.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 15:19:38 -0330</pubDate><guid>https://bryanisonline.github.io/about/</guid><description>Welome, my name is Bryan.
I am a PhD candidate in mathematics at the University of Alberta, whose research lies in the expansive area of quantum algebra and representation theory. The essential idea of my research is to utilize the power of linear algebra to understand and solve more complicated algebraic problems. My mathematical interests also extend to machine learning and cryptography.
Apart from spending extensive time solving mathematical problems, I have a wide array of hobbies and interests, such as coding, biking, skiing, creating/playing music, and attempting to obtain a top 30k finish in fantasy premier league.</description></item></channel></rss>